Beautiful, mysterious, haunting, invariably fatal. Just like life.
The Virgin Suicides is a drama, romance film directed by Sofia Coppola.
A group of male friends become obsessed with five mysterious sisters
who are sheltered by their strict, religious parents.
Lux Lisbon, played by Kirsten Dunst.
Trip Fontaine, played by Josh Hartnett.
Mr. Lisbon, played by James Woods.
Mrs. Lisbon, played by Kathleen Turner.
Adult Trip Fontaine, played by Michael Paré.
Mary Lisbon, played by A. J. Cook.
The Virgin Suicides is a 1999 American psychological romantic drama film written and directed by Sofia
Coppola in her feature directorial debut, and co-produced by her father, Francis Ford Coppola.
Based on the 1993 debut novel by Jeffrey Eugenides, it stars
James Woods, Kathleen Turner, Kirsten Dunst, A.J.
Cook, and Josh Hartnett, with Scott Glenn, Michael Paré,
Jonathan Tucker, and Danny DeVito in supporting roles.
The film follows the lives of five adolescent sisters in an
upper-middle-class suburb of Detroit during 1975.
Shot in 1998 in Toronto, it features an original
score by the French electronic band Air.
The film marked the first collaboration between Sofia Coppola and Kirsten Dunst, whom
Coppola later cast as the lead in several of her subsequent films.
The Virgin Suicides premiered at the 1999 Cannes Film Festival and received a limited theatrical release on
April 21, 2000, in the United States, later expanding to a wide release in May 19, 2000.
The film earned largely positive reviews from critics, with the performances of the
cast, Coppola's direction, visual style, and soundtrack receiving praise.
It was also acclaimed for its lyrical representation of
adolescent angst, and is recognized as a cult classic.
In 2015, the film ranked number 39 on Entertainment Weekly's
list of the "50 Best High School Movies".
The film explores themes of suicide, based on novel or
book, michigan, suicide attempt, 1970s.
The tone is emotional.